<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<issues>
  <issue>
    <field name="Priority">
      <value>Major</value>
    </field>
    <field name="Type">
      <value>Bug</value>
    </field>
    <field name="State">
      <value>Won't fix</value>
    </field>
    <field name="Assignee" />
    <field name="Subsystem">
      <value>ActiveRecord Support</value>
    </field>
    <field name="Fix versions" />
    <field name="Affected versions">
      <value>Release Candidate 3</value>
    </field>
    <field name="Fixed in build" />
    <field name="numberInProject">
      <value>272</value>
    </field>
    <field name="summary">
      <value>Server-side validation failure causes properties on databound object to be null</value>
    </field>
    <field name="description">
      <value>Given a property Username defined like this:

[Property(Access = PropertyAccess.NosetterCamelcaseUnderscore)]
[ValidateNonEmpty("No empty usernames")]
[ValidateIsUnique("Must be unique")]
public string Username { get { return _username; } set { _username = value; } }

and a controller method signature like this:

public void CreateUser([DataBind("User", Validate=true)] User user, string password, string passwordConfirmation, string returnUrl)

If Validate=true on the DataBind attribute and a duplicate value is entered for Username, the data binder puts a null value in Username since it failed validation, and now an attempted Save operation returns a validation error for the ValidateNonEmpty instead of ValidateIsUnique.

If Validate=false, it populates the username field with the duplicate value calls Validator.IsValid(user) return false due to ValidateIsUnique (as expected), but calls to Save are allowed with no failure.

It seems the Save operation should return a validation exception even when Validate=false due to the duplicate username.  I'm not sure what should happen if Validate=true.  Presumably that means to validate the input before the method runs, but how would you indicate to the method that validation problems occurred and what those problems were?  I suppose setting to null would work, but then you run into problems like above where your validation error message might not match what actually went wrong...

For more information, see this post on the forums:  http://forum.castleproject.org/viewtopic.php?p=8185#8185
</value>
    </field>
    <field name="created">
      <value>1181852306000</value>
    </field>
    <field name="updated">
      <value>1244676824000</value>
    </field>
    <field name="reporterName">
      <value>jdcrutchley</value>
    </field>
    <field name="updaterName">
      <value>jdcrutchley</value>
    </field>
    <field name="resolved">
      <value>1282143840479</value>
    </field>
    <field name="permittedGroup">
      <value>All Users</value>
    </field>
    <comment author="kenegozi" text="* '''Status''' changed from ''Resolved'' to ''Closed''.&#xD;&#xA;" created="1244676780000" />
  </issue>
</issues>